Do carrots really help you see in the dark?
胡萝卜真的能帮助你在黑暗中视物吗？
What about kiwis or kale?
猕猴桃或羽衣甘蓝又怎么样呢？
Can eating certain foods improve your eyesight or prevent your eyes degenerating?
吃某些特定的食物能改善视力或者防止眼睛退化吗？
Perhaps we should all be taking supplements to benefit our vision?
也许我们都应该服用一些补剂来改善视力？
Research in both the US and Ireland has shown that supplementing the diet with certain key chemicals can significantly benefit your vision.
美国和爱尔兰的研究都表明，在饮食中补充某些关键化学物质可以显著有益于视力。
These can be taken as supplements but they are also found widely in many green leafy plants and green and yellow fruit and vegetables.
这些物质可以作为补剂服用，但它们也广泛存在于许多绿叶植物以及绿色和黄色的水果和蔬菜中。
The retina is the part of our eye that contains cells sensitive to light.
视网膜是我们眼睛中含有对光敏感细胞的部分。
The most delicate area of this tissue - the macula - is protected from harmful blue and UV light by yellowish 'macular pigment'.
这一组织中最脆弱的区域——黄斑——被淡黄色的“黄斑色素”保护着，免受有害的蓝光和紫外线的伤害。
This acts like sunglasses, blocking the damaging light.
它就像太阳镜一样，阻挡有害光线。
It comprises three pigments - lutein, zeaxanthin and meso-zeaxanthin.
它由三种色素组成——叶黄素、玉米黄质和中玉米黄质。
A research team led by Professor Nolan in Ireland has recently completed a year-long trial investigating the benefits of taking supplements of macular pigments.
由爱尔兰的诺兰教授领导的一个研究团队最近完成了一项为期一年的试验，研究服用黄斑色素补充剂的益处。
100 participants took part in the experiments.
100名参与者参加了实验。
The results showed that by taking lutein, zeaxanthin and meso-zeaxanthin, there was a significant improvement in the protection of the macula, as well as in overall eyesight.
结果表明，通过服用叶黄素、玉米黄质和中玉米黄质，黄斑的保护作用以及整体视力都有了显著改善。
There was also some evidence that these chemicals can help to slow down macular degeneration, which is the main cause of sight loss in the UK.
也有一些证据表明，这些化学物质可以帮助减缓黄斑变性，而黄斑变性是英国视力丧失的主要原因。
However, this is somewhat controversial.
然而，这在某种程度上存在争议。
Lutein is a yellow compound found only in plants, which produce it to absorb light.
叶黄素是一种仅存在于植物中的黄色化合物，植物产生它来吸收光线。
We can get lutein by eating foods like kale and spinach.
我们可以通过食用羽衣甘蓝和菠菜等食物来获取叶黄素。
It is also present in egg yolk.
它也存在于蛋黄中。
Zeaxanthin, another yellow compound similar to lutein, is found in such foods as corn, yellow bell peppers and saffron.
玉米黄质是另一种与叶黄素类似的黄色化合物，存在于诸如玉米、黄甜椒和藏红花等食物中。
Meso-zeaxanthin is not generally found in food sources, though it can be found in some fish.
中玉米黄质一般在食物来源中并不常见，不过在一些鱼类中可以找到。
It is created in the retina from ingested lutein.
它是由摄入的叶黄素在视网膜中生成的。
It can be taken in supplements made with marigold extracts.
它可以通过服用含有万寿菊提取物的补剂来获取。
As for carrots, it turns out that it's the leafy green bits on the top that contain the key compounds beneficial to eyesight, rather than the vegetable itself.
至于胡萝卜，结果证明，对视力有益的关键化合物存在于胡萝卜顶部的绿叶部分，而不是胡萝卜本身。
So next time you're told carrots help you see in the dark, save them for the rabbit and chop up some kiwi instead!
所以下次当有人告诉你胡萝卜能帮助你在黑暗中视物时，把胡萝卜留给兔子，不如切一些猕猴桃吧！